Rafael Magaña García

Pricing & Digital Solutions Expert, Walmart

Islas Carolinas 48-3, Residencial Chiluca, Estado de México, 52930

55 41 88 82 85

rafael.m.g.0491@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/rafaelmg0491 github.com/rafialmadrid rafialmadrid.github.io/myPortfolio

Objective

To become a key player in a challenging environment where I can apply my technical experience to make things work better, faster and more profitable through digital solutions. I always focus my products on having customer centricity and an end-to-end perspective.

Experience

Product Owner (Digital Solutions Manager II), Walmart

February 2020 - present

• Responsible of developing digital solutions for merchandising, replenishment and finance. Currently owner of 3 products: CANELA, Safety Net & Promotional Grill.

Pricing Manager I, Walmart

March 2018 – January 2020

- Responsible of all brick & mortar centralized pricing programs: Merchant Proactivity and Regional Strategies.
- Super-user of an international development that seeks the automation of the most relevant pricing programs.

Pricing Specialist, Walmart

July 2016 – February 2018

 Responsible of groceries pricing strategies and one regional program focused on the most relevant competitor.

Process Engineer Scholar, Walmart

May 2015 - June 2016

• Developed a project to reduce the overall cost on new store developments.

Innovation Scholar, Evenflo

September 2014 - April 2015

Provided support to the product engineers on feeding and gearing projects.

Education

Full Stack Flex Program (Coding Boot Camp), Tecnológico de Monterrey

2020 - 2021

(Web development: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, React.js, Responsive, Bootstrap) (API: JSON, AJAX) (Deployment: Heroku, Git, GitHub Pages) (DB: MySQL, MongoDB) (Servers: Node.js, Express) (QA: testing)

Mechatronics Engineer, Universidad del Valle de México

2012 - 2016

Awarded outstanding performance on final professional exam

Exchange Student, University of Liverpool

2015

Program focused on technological innovation, Business with China and Marketing.

Languages

Spanish – Native English – Advanced

Software

Office – Advanced

Alteryx Designer - Intermediate

SQL – Intermediate Tableu – Basic

Tablea Basic

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, API: JSON, AJAX, Node.js – Basic